samsclubmemberservices.com 2014-11-20

# Privacy Policy - Sam's Club

## Scope:

This policy applies to member information Sam's Club collects in the United States and Puerto Rico, both in Club and through our websites.

Sam's Club has a specific [Notice of Privacy Practices](http://corporate.walmart.com/privacy-security/notices/health-wellness) for its personal information practices relating to our operations in our retail clubs. This Notice is available at each Pharmacy and Optical Center. 

## Information we collect:

We collect your information from the following sources:

  * Information you give us, such as during transactions, Member services, surveys, and online registrations.
  * Information from other sources, such as companies that help us to update our records, and
  * Information automatically collected when you visit our websites, such as via cookies, and in Clubs, such as via video cameras.

Read more about Information We Collect

## How We Use and/or Disclose Your Information:

  * Sam's Club does not sell or rent your personal information.
  * Sam's Club Membership uses your information to provide products and services and to support core business functions. These uses include order or service fulfillment, internal business processes, marketing, authentication, loss and fraud prevention, public safety and legal functions.
  * We may combine all the information we collect. We may disclose your information within our corporate family of companies.
  * We may disclose your personal information to third parties under the following limited circumstances: 
    * with service providers or suppliers that help with our business operations or joint products;
    * with the company that we partner with to offer credit card programs, if you apply for Sam's Membership, to help you obtain the highest credit limit possible this may include your Membership and application information;
    * with carefully selected companies who may offer you products and services of interest, you may opt-out of this sharing;
    * in order to respond to Member inquiries from the account's primary Member or from an officer or principal of a Business Member;
    * for certain business Members who purchase business resale merchandise, such as tobacco products, we may share information with our partners in order to enable them to offer such customers discounts or rebates.
    * with your consent, and
    * when necessary to protect the safety, property, or other rights of Sam's Club, Members, or associates, or when otherwise required by law;
    * we may transfer any information we have about you in connection with a merger or sale (including transfers made as part of insolvency or bankruptcy proceedings) involving all or part of Sam's Club or as part of a corporate reorganization or stock sale or other change in corporate control.

Read more about How We Use and/or Share Your Information

## Your choices:

  * We want to communicate with you in ways you want to hear from us. Examples include email newsletters, special offers, and new product announcements. We use the following communication standards: 
    * We will not contact you via text message without your express consent (opt in),
    * We use an opt-out standard for all other marketing communications. This means we will conduct the activity unless you tell us not to. (opt out). Learn more about how to opt out in the "Your Choices" section below.
  * Information from other sources, such as companies that help us to update our records, and
  * Information automatically collected when you visit our websites, such as via cookies, and in Clubs, such as via video cameras.

Read more about Information We Collect

[Member Services](http://samsclubanswercenter.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/167) \- for Club experience, marketing preferences, product questions and general feedback/questions.

[Email Privacy Office](mailto:privacy@samsclub.com) \- for privacy or Sam's Club Privacy Policy feedback/questions. 

Sam's Club recognizes the importance of our Members' privacy. We believe that privacy is more than an issue of compliance - it is one of trust. We strive to manage your personal information based on our basic belief of respect for the individual. This policy describes:

  * How and why we collect your personal information.
  * How your information is used and protected.
  * When and with whom we share your information.
  * The choices you can make about how we collect, use, and share your information.

## Notice and Scope of Our Privacy Practices

Our goal is to provide clear, prominent, and easily accessible information about our privacy practices. This policy applies to Member information obtained by Sam's Club in connection with its operations, both in Clubs and online, in the United States and Puerto Rico.

Sam's Club has a specific [Notice of Privacy Practices](http://corporate.walmart.com/privacy-security/notices/health-wellness) for its personal information practices relating to our Health and Wellness operations in our retail clubs. This Notice is available at each Pharmacy and Optical Center. 

## Information We Collect

We collect personal information about you to deliver the products and services you request and to help improve your shopping experience. We strive to limit the amount of personal information collected to support the intended purpose of the collection.

### Information You Give Us

We collect personal information from you in a variety of ways when you interact with Sam's Club, both in Clubs and online. Some examples are when you:

  * Sign up for a Sam's Club Membership;
  * Make an online or in-Club purchase from us;
  * Use a gift registry;
  * Conduct a transaction where we collect information, including when required by law (such as purchasing certain cold medications);
  * Request Member service or contact us;
  * Submit a Sam's Club related story, testimonial, rating or review, or other user-generated content that may be posted on the site;
  * Participate in a contest, sweepstake, promotion, or survey; or
  * Otherwise submit personal information to us along with any related content of the communication.

Personal information is information that identifies you or is reasonably linked to you. The personal information we collect may include contact and payment information like your name, email and physical addresses, phone numbers, and credit and debit card information. When you ask us to ship an order, we may collect information you provide us such as the name, address, and phone number of recipients. For certain transactions, we may be required to collect information to comply with legal requirements.

We receive personal information about you from other sources. This information helps us to correct or supplement our records, improve the quality or personalization of our service to you, and prevent or detect fraud. We collect personal information from consumer reporting agencies in conjunction with products or services that involve financial risk to Sam's Club.

### Automated Information Collection

We receive and store certain types of information when you interact with our websites, emails, and online advertising. Our purpose is to allow the websites to work correctly, to evaluate use of the website, and to support website analytics and marketing campaigns. Some examples include:

  * We may collect technical information such as your internet protocol address, your computer's operating system and browser type, the address of a referring website, if any, and the path you take through our web pages.
  * We use "cookies" to recognize you as you use or return to our sites. This is done so that we can provide a continuous and more personalized shopping experience for you. A cookie is a small text file that a website or email may save to your browser on your hard drive.
  * We may also use web beacons. Beacons allow us to know if a certain page was visited, an email was opened, or if ad banners on our website and other sites were effective.

Our Clubs utilize cameras for security and operational purposes, such as to measure traffic patterns. Except for security purposes, we do not use these cameras to identify you personally.

### How We Use Your Information

Sam's Club uses your information to offer and provide our products and services and to support our core business functions. These include order or service fulfillment, internal business processes, marketing, authentication, loss and fraud prevention, public safety and legal functions. Some examples include:

  * To fulfill your requests for products and services and communicate with you about those requests;
  * To register and service your account;
  * To administer surveys, sweepstakes, contests, and promotions;
  * To provide Member service and alert you to product information, including recalls;
  * To help us improve and customize our service offerings, websites, and advertising;
  * To send you information about our products, services, and promotions; and
  * To protect the security or integrity of our websites and our business.

To accomplish these purposes, we may combine personal and non-personal information we collect online with offline information, including information from third parties. We may transfer or disclose your information within our corporate family of companies for these purposes.

Sam's Club may also receive and share information within the family of Walmart companies to better understand Member needs and improves services. 

### How We Disclose Your Information Outside Sam's Club

Sam's Club does not sell or rent your personal information to third parties. We only disclose your personal information with your prior consent or under the following limited circumstances.

#### Service Providers

We may disclose or otherwise make available personal information about you to service providers that help with our business operations. Examples are shipping vendors, billing and refund vendors, payment card processors, and companies that help us improve our product and service offerings and our websites. Your personal information may be stored and processed by our service providers in the United States or other locations where the service providers or Sam's Club maintain facilities. We require our service providers to keep your information secure. In addition, our service providers may not use or disclose personal information for any purpose other than providing the services on our behalf.

#### Legal Requirements and Protection of Our Company and Others

We may disclose your information in other special circumstances. These include situations when the sharing is necessary to protect the safety, property, or other rights of Sam's Club, our Members, our associates, or any other person, or where otherwise required by law. Examples include protecting the health or safety of Members, or addressing crimes committed on Sam's Club property. Data from in-Club security cameras may also be provided to law enforcement upon written request. Sam's Club may provide your personal information in response to a search warrant or other legally valid inquiry or order, or to an investigative body in the case of a breach of an agreement or contravention of law, or as otherwise required by applicable law.

#### Credit Offers

If you apply for a Sam's Club Membership, we may share your information with the company that we partner with to offer credit card programs. To help you obtain the highest credit limit possible this may include your Membership and application information. Similarly, if you qualify for a credit account and are not offered a credit account by a Sam's Club Associate we may share your information with our partner, so that they may extend the offer of credit as required by law. However, you can choose to stop receiving prescreened offers of consumer credit from all companies, including prescreened offers of Sam's Club credit, by calling 1.888.567.8688.

#### Marketing Purposes

From time to time, we may disclose information with carefully selected companies who may offer you products and services of interest. To opt out of this sharing click here and follow the instructions. These opt-outs do not apply to the Sam's Club co-branded credit card or to data sharing regarding business customers that purchase business resale merchandise.

#### Business Member Inquiries

We may share information regarding a Business Membership with the account's primary Member or an Officer or Principal of the business in order to respond to their inquiry.

We may share information about Business Members resale merchandise purchases, such as tobacco products, with our partners in order to enable them to offer such customers discounts or rebates. 

#### Products and Services Offered by Other Businesses

We sometimes enable other businesses to make products or services available to our members. You may purchase products or services from these other businesses at our Clubs or through our websites or mobile services. We indicate when products or services are offered by other businesses and share with these businesses personal information related to the provision of their products and services. 

#### Business Transfers

We may transfer any information we have about you in connection with a merger or sale (including transfers made as part of insolvency or bankruptcy proceedings) involving all or part of Sam's Club or as part of a corporate reorganization or stock sale or other change in corporate control.

### Your Choices

#### Data Collection, Use, or Disclosure

Sam's Club collects, uses, or discloses your personal information consistent with this policy. The method of obtaining consent is appropriate for the type of personal information being collected, used, or disclosed. For example, we will obtain your express consent (verbal, written, or electronic agreement) to collect, use, or disclose personal health information in accordance with law. In other situations, we consider consent to be implied, such as to use your email for marketing purposes, unless you opt out of these communications such as by unsubscribing.

#### Marketing Preferences

We want to communicate with you in ways you want to hear from us. Examples are newsletters, special offers, and new product announcements. We use the following communication standards:

  * We use an opt-in standard for text messages. Opt-in means we will only conduct the activity with your express consent.
  * We use an opt-out standard for email or for other marketing communications like mail. Opt-out means we consider your consent is implied, but will not conduct the activity on your request.

You may opt-out of receiving different types of Sam's Club marketing material in the following ways

  * Online: By logging on to your samsClub.com account and clicking "edit" on the Member profile section.
  * By Email: You may email [privacy@samsClub.com](mailto:privacy@samsclub.com) for assistance.
  * By Mail: Sam's Club, 2101 SE Simple Savings Drive, Bentonville, AR 72716-0745, Attention: Membership Department
  * By Phone: You may call Member Services by dialing 1.888.746.7726.
  * In Club: You may request to opt out at the Membership desk of your local Sam's Club.

If you contact us by email or mail, please be sure to include your full name, Membership number, and the types of communications you would like to receive or not receive, and your related contact information. For instance, if you would like to opt out of mail, include your mailing address. Please allow sufficient time for your preferences to be processed. It may take up to 10 days to process your requests related to email and up to 30 days to process your requests related to telephone calls, text messages, and fax messages. Please note that postal mailings are often prepared many weeks in advance, and you may continue to receive mail for 6-10 weeks.

Since we do not accept opt out request from third parties, such as catalog opt-out services, please communicate your request directly to us through one of the mechanism mentioned above.

Please be aware that, even if you have opted out of receiving marketing communications from us, we may still contact you for transactional purposes. Some examples are contacts for Member service, product information, service or reminder notices, or recalls. We may also need to contact you with questions or information regarding your order, such as regarding order status, shipment, or refunds. 

#### How to Access and Update Your Information

Sam's Club takes reasonable steps to keep your personal information accurate and complete. You can access or update your personal information, including contact or account information, in the following ways:

  * If you have created an account on one of our websites, log into your account. Once you do, you will be able to enter and update your own contact information and payment information, as well as contact information for recipients you have designated.
  * Contact us at the email or postal address listed in the "Contact Us" section at the bottom of this policy. Please include your current contact information, the information you are interested in accessing, and your requested changes. We will provide you the personal information requested if reasonably available, unless it infringes on the privacy of other individuals and subject to reasonable limitations provided by law and internal procedures. Otherwise we will describe the types of information we typically collect. We will provide access and make changes you request, or will provide an explanation of what actions we will be able to take with regard to the request.
  * If you need help accessing your information related to a service provided by a third party, we will assist you by referring you to the third party. Please contact us via the "Contact Us" section below.
  * If you need assistance accessing records related to your Vision Center, Pharmacy, or financial services information, please visit the section below related to "Privacy Protections for Specific Types of Information."
  * You can deactivate your Sam's Club account if you wish. Please contact our Member Service Department by calling 1 (888) 746-7726 for further instructions about deactivating your Samsclub.com account.

#### Joint or Co-branded Marketing Material:

We may also share your personal information with partners when we team up to offer or provide products, services, contests, or promotions that are of value to Members. If you would like to opt-out of this type of sharing, [click here](http://www.samsclub.com/sams/account/privacyOptOut.jsp) and follow the instructions.

Please note your choice to opt-out under any of the above will apply only to the individual cardholder Membership. If there are several cardholder Memberships under a single Account (such as a spouse's card or add-on card), each person with a Membership card must opt-out. 

#### Credit offerings

The above marketing preferences do not apply to our credit card offerings since these are provided through our financial institution partner(s). However, you can choose to stop receiving prescreened offers of credit from all companies, including our prescreened offers, by calling 1.888.567.8688 or by going to [www.optoutprescreen.com](http://www.optoutprescreen.com/).

#### Online Operations and Advertising

You may exercise choices related to our online operations and advertising. For instance, you can choose to browse our websites without accepting cookies Please know that cookies allow us to recognize you from page to page, and they support your transactions with us. Without cookies enabled, you will still be able to browse our websites, but will not be able to complete a purchase or take advantage of certain website features.

To learn more about cookies, including how to refuse cookies on your computer, follow these links: 

You may also opt-out of certain online advertising called interest-based advertising. Interest-based ads are ads that are served to you based on your browsing behavior. The goal is to show you ads more tailored to your interests.

We may use how you browse and shop in order to show you advertisements on our website that are more relevant to your interests. As an example, if you browse for electronics with us or other sites, we may show you ads for electronics as you browse our website. Advertisements may relate to Sam's Club or our advertising partners. We do not disclose personal data about you with advertising partners to place an ad for them. We only retain data related to the ads for legitimate business purposes.

In addition, we belong to ad networks that may use your browsing history across participating websites to show you interest-based advertisements on those websites. You may see ads for Sam's Club on participating websites based on how you browse our website and those sites. We do not allow the network provider to provide your browsing behavior on our website to other websites.

You may opt-out of either interest-based advertising on our website, or interest-based advertising on other sites, as described above. Other websites you visit may offer their own opt-out methods as well. If you do opt-out of interest-based advertisements, you may still see advertisements on websites you visit, just not ads based on your browsing behavior. 

#### About Our Ads

**Ads Displayed on SamsClub.com**  
Sam's Club may use how you browse and shop in order to show you ads for Sam's Club or our advertising partners that are more relevant to your interests. Learn more about your options, including how to opt out of this type of advertising.

**Please note:** If you choose to opt out, you will continue to see ads on SamsClub.com, but they will not be based on how you browse and shop.

**Sam's Club Ads Displayed on Other Sites**  
Some websites may belong to ad networks that use your browsing history across websites to choose which ads to display on their sites; the displayed ads may include advertising for Sam's Club. To learn more, and to opt out of seeing interest-based advertisements on these sites, visit the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) home page. Websites may also offer their own opt-out methods for interest-based advertising. 

#### Sam's Club Advertising

Sam's Club may use how you browse and shop in order to show you ads that are more relevant to your interests.

If you [choose to opt out](http://www.samsclub.com/sams/account/privacyOptOut.jsp), you will continue to see ads while browsing SamsClub.com, but they will not be based on how you browse and shop.

**Cookie Status:**  
Your current settings allow you to see interest-based advertisements while browsing or shopping on SamsClub.com.

Once you have opted out, we will no longer use your browsing and shopping behavior to select which ads are displayed to you on SamsClub.com. You will continue to see ads on our site. 

  * To successfully opt out, you must have cookies enabled in your Web browser (see your browser's instructions for information on cookies and how to enable them).
  * Opting out only applies to your current Web browser on your current computer. If you use multiple computers or multiple Web browsers, you must opt out using each one.
  * Once you opt out, if you delete your browser's saved cookies, you will need to opt out again.

### How to Access and Update Your Information

Sam's Club takes reasonable steps to keep your personal information accurate and complete. You can access or update your personal information, including contact or account information, in the following ways:

  * If you have created an account on one of our websites, log into your account. Once you do, you will be able to enter and update your own contact information and payment information, as well as contact information for recipients you have designated.
  * Contact us at the email or postal address listed in the "Contact Us" section at the bottom of this policy. Please include your current contact information, the information you are interested in accessing, and your requested changes. We will provide you the personal information requested if reasonably available, unless it infringes on the privacy of other individuals and subject to reasonable limitations provided by law and internal procedures. Otherwise we will describe the types of information we typically collect. We will provide access and make changes you request, or will provide an explanation of what actions we will be able to take with regard to the request.
  * If you need help accessing your information related to a service provided by a third party, we will assist you by referring you to the third party. Please contact us via the "Contact Us" section below.
  * If you need assistance accessing records related to your Optical, Pharmacy, or financial services information, please visit the section below related to "Privacy Protections for Specific Types of Information."

### How We Secure Your Information

Securing your information is a company priority. Whether you are shopping online or in our Clubs, we use reasonable security measures to help protect the confidentiality of personal information.

#### Online Protections

Your account information is protected by the password you use to access your online account. Please keep this password confidential. We also use a technology called Secure Sockets Layer (SSL). If your browser is capable of SSL (and most are), your account information will be protected during transport across the Internet. When you enter a secure portion of a website, which is any page containing any of your account information, an image of a closed lock or a solid key should appear in the bottom bar of your browser window. If you click on this image, a small pop-up window displaying website security information will appear. This display indicates that your personal information is transmitted in encrypted form to a Sam's Club web server, not to some unknown or unauthorized server.

#### Hard Copy and Electronic Storage Protections

Personal information that is maintained in our offices or Clubs is subject to physical, administrative, and technical controls as well. Hard copies of sensitive personal information are maintained in locked locations or cabinets with similar restrictions for electronic storage. When disposed of, the information is shredded, destroyed, erased, or otherwise sought to be made unreadable.

### Privacy Protections for Specific Types of Information

#### Pharmacy and Optical Centers

When you use our Pharmacy and Optical Center services, you may provide us with your health information so that we may process your request. We understand the sensitive nature of such information and respect your privacy by keeping it confidential in accordance with laws and our policies. Our [Notice of Privacy Practices](http://corporate.walmart.com/privacy-security/notices/health-wellness) for personal health information describes how we protect the information and how you may access it. This notice is provided to you by the Pharmacy or Optical Center at the first time of service or can be requested at any time at your local Sam's Club.

#### Financial Products and Services

When you obtain financial products and services from us, and our partner, GE Capital Retail Bank (GECRB), we may collect and use certain financial-related information. We understand the sensitive nature of this information as well, and protect it in accordance with laws and our policies. Find out more about [GECRB's Privacy Policy](https://chb.onlinecreditcenter6.com/dualcardimages/dualcard/sams/en/html//Privacy.html).

We protect payment card information we collect during transactions. We comply with industry standards that require safeguards for handling and securing Member information. These include using secure networks; encryption or other protection of cardholder data; physical and technical access controls; monitors and tests of security systems; and information security policies. 

### Changes to the Sam's Club Privacy Policy

Please check our privacy policy periodically for changes. We will also notify you of significant updates and will post the date it was last updated at the bottom of the privacy policy.

### Contact Us

Email [Member Services](http://samsclubanswercenter.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/167) \- for Club experience, marketing preferences and general feedback/questions.

#### Contacting the Privacy Office

[Email Privacy Office](mailto:privacy@samsclub.com) \- Please feel free to contact the privacy office with any questions or comments about this policy or about how your information is handled. You can also contact us via the addresses below:

  * **Mail:**  
Sam's Club Corporate  
Privacy Office, MS #505  
508 SW 8th Street  
Bentonville, AR 72716-0160

### Your California Privacy Rights

Our privacy policy describes how we share information for marketing purposes. The policy and rights apply to all Members, including California residents:

  * We share information with others outside of Sam's Club, unless you ask us not to (opt-out). See How We Share Your Information Outside Sam's Club.
  * We also share information with other businesses within our corporate family, such as Walmart. See How We Use Your Information.

Please contact us with any questions, or to request a list of third parties to whom we may disclose information for marketing purposes and the categories of information we may disclose, via the Contact Us section above.

Effective: October 15, 2014
